Seventeen Poker  Fourth Hand
Counterattack
Huh?
Kikuchi said knowing where the joker
is would let him win for sure...
Is it really that helpful?
Akiyama got to cut second this hand,
so the chances of them drawing
the joker are even, right?
That's right.
And in fact, the joker isn't
in Kikuchi's hand right now.
Right?
Even if the joker doesn't go
to one of them to begin with,
the chances of either one
drawing it from the deck
are still fifty-fifty.
You're wrong.
When Kikuchi gets to draw first,
there's a 100% chance that
Akiyama's not drawing the joker.
Let's say the joker is
on top of the deck.
Kikuchi knows it's the joker,
so if he draws first,
he's guaranteed to get it.
I understand that much, but...
You may now draw cards.
Kikuchi-san?
I'll discard all five, then.
His whole hand?! Why?!
Because the joker is the fifth card down.
You see now, don't you?
If the joker is in the top five cards,
Kikuchi will always be able to get it.
But if it's the sixth or seventh
card, won't Akiyama get it?
Not likely.
In Seventeen Poker, the worst hand
you can start with is a pair.
Which means Akiyama is unlikely
to ask for more than three cards.
I get it!
Kikuchi can just ask for one or two.
Then, since his opponent
won't draw more than three,
the last two cards go untouched!
In other words, no matter where
the joker is in the deck,
Akiyama's never getting it.
Kikuchi has overwhelmingly better
odds of getting the joker.
But isn't scrapping his
whole hand kinda risky?
Not at all.
In the last draw, Akiyama took two cards.
In other words, all seventeen
cards have been used.
Right...
Of those seventeen,
Kikuchi has seen ten of them.
He can calculate back from that to figure
which seven his opponent has seen.
No matter how you combine
those seven cards,
the best he could have is two pairs.
Kikuchi's victory is a certainty.
Open!
Eastern Army - Two Pair
Western Army - Three of a Kind
Yes!
Kikuchi wins the fourth hand.
Chip Divide
chip
Eastern Army lead
Twenty chips go to the Western Army.
We will now begin the fifth hand.
He got the joker!
And four of a kind!
Kikuchi-san, the first bet is yours.
I fold.
The fifth hand is incomplete.
Chip Divide
chip
Eastern Army lead
Both five-chip antes go to the dealer.
The chip balance does not change.
We had such a good hand, too...
What do we do? Those precious
chips went to the dealer...
What happened there?
His opponent drew the joker.
If he folds, he basically forces a tie.
And, having folded, he'll cut
second in the next hand.
He can arrange to nab the
joker in his opening hand.
I get it.
Sixth Hand
You see?
Incredible.
The first round of betting is complete.
Now, open!
Western Army - Four of a Kind
Eastern Army - Full House
Yes!
The Western Army wins
the sixth hand, as well.
Chip Divide
chip
Eastern Army lead
Twenty chips go to the Western Army,
who now takes the lead.
Chip Divide
chip
Western Army lead
The Core match is ours!
You...
can see the joker, can't you?
Wha...
What are you talking about?
You should've kept that under wraps.
You're being way too obvious about it.
Drawing four cards in the practice round
and five in the fourth hand just now...
Then folding when the joker
was in my hand to start...
There's only one way
to explain your behavior.
You know where the joker is.
Impossible.
They open a new pack each hand.
There's no way to cheat.
It's just your imagination.
But of course, it's human nature
to get jumpy when you're losing.
I see.
Maybe I am just getting jumpy.
Time-out!
The Eastern Army calls their time-out.
You will have three minutes to plan.
Looks like you're not the
only one feeling jumpy.
The Core match is as good as ours!
He's caught on.
He's realized I know where the joker is.
Will you be all right?
Oh, please.
Even if he's caught on,
there's nothing he can do about it.
Only I can use this trick.
Players of the Western Army!
What's this all about?
Please, can we call a truce?
We want to save you!
Where's this coming from?
Hang on. Let's hear her out.
We intentionally ended the
Spearhead match in a tie.
Do you understand why?
To secure our victory,
we would have had to pass,
and a lot of chips would
have gone to the dealer.
In terms of the total pot, we,
the players, would have lost out.
What are you talking about? "Total pot"?
In this revival round,
they handed out 900 million in chips
but are only collecting 600 million.
We have a chance to nab
that bonus 300 million.
If we don't fight, that 300 million
can save multiple people.
If you'll agree to concede to us,
we'll use it all to save the three of you!
That's ridiculous.
I think she means it.
It's the only reason they'd go for
a draw in the Spearhead match.
Are you kidding?
Nobody would shoot themselves
in the foot to save someone else!
Please!
Drop it.
They're not going to go for it.
But...
Your time to strategize is up.
Both players please...
Seventh Hand
Hey.
Is what that Kanzaki girl said true?
About saving us?
Yeah.
That would certainly be nice.
You hear that?
He might accept our proposal!
Now, your first bet, please.
I bet the maximum: fifteen chips.
What will you do, Akiyama-san?
I'm sure you're going to call, right?
Can't let the dealer take those chips
if you really want to save us, right?
I call.
That's the way.
I've got a bad feeling about this.
Your second bet, please.
The maximum thirty chips!
Akiyama-san.
You wanna save us, right?
The five cards in my hand...
They're absolute shit.
You'll win this one for sure.
No way you're dropping out now, right?
Call.
Incredible. A big play
for a full pot of fifty chips!
Now, open!
Kikuchi of the Western Army
wins with four queens.
Like I'd ever give myself a garbage hand!
I knew the joker was
the second card down.
Since I always know where the joker is,
I'm invincible in this game!
Nao! This is all your fault!
Because you told him we can't
let chips go to the dealer!
So even when Akiyama can't win,
he can't fold, either!
N-No...
Another fifty chips to the Western Army.
Chip Divide
chip
Western Army lead
The divide is now 118 chips.
With a mere three hands left
to play, the gulf has grown wide.
I very kindly called
on that fifty-chip bet,
and you'd mock me for it?
I suppose I'll really have to crush you.
We will now begin the eighth hand.
Wait a minute.
You've been letting the cards show.
Kikuchi's winning because
he memorizes the cards
he sees when you do the Hindu shuffle.
What?! Don't make things up
just because you're losing!
I'm not making anything up.
You clearly know where the joker is.
Is he serious?!
The LGT Office wants these
games to be fair, correct?
Well, yes...
Why not stick to only
the riffle shuffle, then?
You won't be holding up the cards,
so he won't be able to see them.
If you want to prove your innocence,
I'm sure you'll agree to that.
Okay.
I agree to just a riffle shuffle.
If you please, then.
What an idiot!
He can't stop my foolproof plan that way!
The riffle shuffle is even easier
to follow than the Hindu!
From here on out,
it's every man for himself.
I'll engage in these last
hands with cold logic...
and destroy you.
Is that right?
Boast all you want!
No matter how you struggle,
I'll still win the day!
The joker is the fourth card down.
Your first bet, please.
If I want to make sure
he stays in the game,
I need him to think my hand is bad.
Keep the bet small...
Five chips.
Five? Huh.
Akiyama-san, if you please.
The maximum fifteen chips.
Kikuchi-san?
I call.
He stayed in the game because
I kept my bet small!
You may now draw cards.
He won't take more than three.
I'll get the joker no matter what.
I'll discard my whole hand.
What?!
He's ended up with the joker!
Kikuchi-san, how many
cards would you like?
One, please.
This hand's better than I expected!
The problem is Akiyama, though...
Akiyama-san, your second bet, please.
If he raises big, I'll fold.
I'll stick with fifteen.
He's not raising?
Maybe his hand's not so great?
I guess I got lucky!
Kikuchi-san, if you please.
Call.
Then... open!
The West has a full house.
The East, four of a kind.
The Eastern Army takes the eighth hand.
The chip differential is now 48.
Chip Divide
chip
Western Army lead
Akiyama-san is amazing!
It was inevitable that I'd
lose like that eventually.
Actually, it's to my benefit!
Losing that hand gives
me the second cut.
Cutting second means I can get
the joker in my opening hand!
In other words, I'll win for sure!
We will now begin the ninth hand.
Right. I'm turning it around now.
Whatever you say!
I'll hang you with this hand.
I will now deal the cards.
Wait a minute.
Kikuchi peeked at the cards
in that shuffle just now.
Shuffle them again, please.
More of your excuses?!
What shall I do, Kikuchi-san?
I didn't expect him
to harp on it like this,
but it's better than refusing
and looking like a cheater.
Go ahead.
Will that do?
That should be fine.
The cut, then. Akiyama-san first.
Five cards, then.
Four cards.
That cut has moved the joker
from the top to the fourth card.
Akiyama
Kikuchi
The deal will start with Akiyama,
and the joker will come to me!
I already have three aces!
And now, the first round of betting.
I'll check.
Check?!
He wants to hold off and evaluate my hand?
Let's keep it small.
Eight chips.
Eight? Unexpectedly small.
I'll call, then.
He's taken the bait!
Kikuchi-san, you may now draw.
I'll take two cards.
A full house, aces high!
Great insurance!
Akiyama-san?
I'll take five, then.
Five cards?!
What's with him?
Is he just getting desperate?
The second round of betting
will start with Kikuchi-san.
If I want to finish him off,
I have to make sure he calls.
To do that, I have to act
like my hand is bad...
I'll bet... eight.
Eight, hmm?
And you, Akiyama-san?
I'll raise.
To the upper limit of thirty chips.
This guy's a bona fide moron!
He thinks my hand is
weak, so he's all in!
I've never seen a bigger
rube in all my life!
What will you do, Kikuchi-san?
I suppose I'll have to call.
I can't stop smiling!
The hand is complete, with a
whopping 43 chips on the line!
Now...
Open!
Die, Akiyama!
Western Army - Full House
Eastern Army - Four of a Kind
Akiyama wins.
He did it!
The Eastern Army finally
turns things around.
Chip Divide
chip
Eastern Army lead
The match will now be decided
by the tenth and final hand.
That was the dumbest of dumb luck.
There's no way he'll draw four of
a kind on a five-card draw again.
And for the final hand,
I get to cut second.
I can guarantee the joker
in my opening hand!
Akiyama's losing for sure!
We will now begin the final hand.
I can win if the game plays out.
But will he actually ride it out?
Don't worry.
I'll stay in.
You're worried I'll fold on the tenth hand
to eke out a win in the Core match, right?
Don't worry. I won't cut and run.
The Spearhead match was a draw, remember?
The important thing now
isn't scrounging a win,
but securing a large pot of chips so a
loss in the General match won't stop us.
Momentum is on my side at the moment,
so if I think I can win, I'll definitely
be looking to take a fifty-chip windfall.
Momentum's on his side, huh?
Thank goodness he's so stupid!
The joker is the ninth card down.
Wait.
This is the final hand.
Let's avoid any chance
for doubt or resentment.
Shuffle them three more times.
This again?!
I-I mean...
Will that clear me in your mind?
Yes.
Then do it.
As you wish.
Now, the cut.
Akiyama-san first.
Eight cards, then.
Seven cards.
The joker is sixth from the top.
It'll come to me in my first hand!
Aces-high full house!
It's such a great hand, I can't
stop myself from grinning!
The question is...
Will Akiyama stay in the game?
Now, the first round of betting.
Fifteen chips.
Didn't I tell you?
I'm going all in if I think I can win.
I'm saved!
His gambler's mindset is my salvation!
He means to see this through to the end!
And you, Kikuchi-san?
Well, since I'm behind and all,
I suppose I'll just have to call.
We'll now draw cards.
Akiyama-san?
I'll discard my whole hand.
Is that a problem?
Um, no...
He went all in with a trash hand?
Or is he trading it out to increase
his odds of getting the joker?
Too bad it's already with me!
Still, this is tricky...
Since he drew five, if I draw two,
we'll have gone through
all seventeen cards.
He'll realize I have the joker,
and he'll drop out.
I should stay strong, keep my hand,
and act like the joker is one
of the cards still in the deck.
All five cards, huh?
Maybe my lousy hand
stands a chance after all.
Okay, I'll keep my hand.
It's possible I could improve
my hand by drawing,
but then you might fold, so...
I'll face you down with
this mediocre hand!
Did my performance convince him?
Or was it too obvious?!
Now, the second round of betting.
Akiyama-san, if you please.
I'm begging you, stay in!
Then...
I'm in with thirty chips.
What did you just say?
I said I'm putting in the
maximum bet. Thirty chips.
Really?
I won... with the power of my acting!
Kikuchi-san, what will you do?
I have no choice. I'll have to call.
Then the hand is complete.
You're an idiot, Akiyama!
Now that the hand is complete,
I'll tell you everything!
You were right all along!
I knew exactly where the joker was!
This hand is mine!
Next Time
General Match